Okay, so welcome to our leaderboard fast as we go through a ton of essential leaderboards for your
네, 순위표에 오신 걸 환영합니다 여러분의 컬렉션에 필요한 필수 순위표를 살펴보고 있는데요
The first of them, the Big Code Models leaderboard.
그 중 첫 번째는 빅 코드 모델의 leaderboard죠
You can see the URL there, but you can also just search for it in hugging face.
URL 보이시죠? 하지만 안는 얼굴에서 검색할 수도 있어요
Um, and as with all of them, it's running as a spaces um, app.
다른 것들처럼 스페이스 앱으로 실행되고 있어요
And also we'll include links in the class resources.
클래스 리소스에 링크도 포함시킬 거예요
Um, so what you see here is the, uh, set of models.
여기 보시는 건 모형 세트예요
Let me start by filtering just on base models.
베이스 모델에서 필터링부터 할게요
So it's names that we all recognize.
우리 모두 아는 이름이죠
And you see the scores against the, uh, set of the human eval tests that I mentioned before, which
그리고 점수를 보면 앞서 언급했던 인체 평가 시험 세트인 파이썬 테스트와
is Python tests and then tests against Java and JavaScript and C plus plus.
자바스크립트 테스트 C 플러스 테스트가 있죠
So you can compare the performance of these models in against different programming languages.
이 모델의 성능을 다른 프로그래밍 언어와 비교할 수 있어요
And the win rate is a sort of a similar to like an average across them.
승률은 전체의 평균과 비슷하다고 할 수 있죠
And if you go to the about page, you'll get more information about how those are figured out and the,
get each 페이지로 가시면 더 많은 정보를 얻을 수 있습니다. 이 열을 계산하는
the way that this this column is calculated, you can see that the top model for coding is a specialized
방식을 보면 코딩의 가장 윗부분이 코드를 작성하기 위한 퀸의 특수 버전인 것을 볼 수 있습니다.
version of Queen for writing code that is called code Queen.
이것을 코드 퀸이라고 부르죠.
And there's also a code llama that's not far behind.
근처에 라마 코드도 있어요
Deep Sea Coder is a model that's doing very well.
심해 코더는 아주 잘 나가는 모델이에요
Uh, a variant of Code Llama.
코드 라마의 변종이죠
And then Star Coder two is the model that we used ourselves early on.
스타 코더 2는 초기에 우리가 사용한 모델이죠
And so Star Coder two features here as well.
스타 코더 2의 기능도 여기 있고요
Um, and then Code Gemma, which is Google's open source code generation model.
다음은 코드 젬마 구글의 오픈 소스 코드 생성 모델이죠
If we include all, then we'll include some of the ones that have been, uh, tuned specifically on
전부를 포함하면 좀 더 구체적인 데이터 세트에 맞춰 조정된 일부도
more specific data sets.
포함할 거예요
And you'll see that actually, if you compare the scores, uh, it really Yeah.
점수를 비교해 보면 알 수 있어요
There's been a see that the code is far down now that a lot have been fine tuned to do much better.
요즘 코드는 훨씬 더 낮아졌고 많은 것들이 더 잘 튜닝되었어요
Um, somewhat surprisingly, Code Kwan 1.5 chat uh, seems to be, uh, outperforming the 1.5, uh,
좀 놀랍지만 코드 콴 1이에요 채팅 5개가 1을 능가하는 것 같아요 여기에는 50억 70억 명이 있어요
um, 7 billion down here, but but there may be various reasons for that.
하지만 여러 가지 이유가 있을 수 있죠
It might be to do with the way the data set that's been used to fine train it for that purpose, um,
그 목적으로 데이터를 훈련하는 데 사용된 방식 때문일 수도 있고 여기서
along with the kinds of questions that are asked here.
제기되는 질문 때문일 수도 있어요
So if the specific problem you're looking to solve involves coding the big code models, leaderboard,
여러분이 풀어야 할 문제가 대형 코드 모델 코딩과 관련 있다면 leaderboard가
is the leaderboard for you.
딱이죠
Next one we're going to look at is called the LM perf leaderboard, which is about looking at the performance
다음은 LM 향기 리더보드입니다 속도나 메모리 소비량
of different models around things like their speed, their memory consumption and the like.
같은 것에 관련된 다양한 모델의 성능을 살펴보는 거죠
And if you go to the leaderboard itself, you find the models listed out here with their various variations
leaderboard를 보면 다양한 변형이 있는 모델들이 나와 있습니다
and then information about their speed, their consumption of energy and memory and so on.
속도, 에너지 소비량 메모리 사용량 등 정보도 있고요
But I would actually suggest that you don't start with with with that page, but instead you flip to
하지만 제가 권하고 싶은 것은 그 페이지에서 시작하지 말고 이 페이지로 넘어가서
this, find your best model, you choose the hardware architecture that you're looking at, and then
최고의 모델을 찾는 것입니다. 당신이 보고 있는 하드웨어 구조를
you pick find your best model and what you see here when you go to find your best model is this very
선택하고, 최고의 모델을 고릅니다. 여기 보이는 것은 매우 흥미로운
interesting chart, which is actually a diagram that's displaying, uh, at least three different,
도표입니다. 다이어그램으로 적어도 세 가지의 양을 보여주고 있죠.
But if not, you could argue for, uh, along the x axis.
그렇지 않다면 엑스 축을 따라야겠죠
Here you are seeing something about the speed.
여기서 속도에 대한 뭔가를 보게 되죠
It's the time that this model takes to generate 64 tokens.
이 모델이 토큰 64개를 생성하는 데 걸리는 시간이죠
So obviously the more to the left is better.
왼쪽으로 더 기울일수록 좋아요
It means faster time.
시간이 단축되니까요
We're looking for models that come to the left if you care about performance, uh, speed, performance.
왼쪽으로 오는 모델을 찾고 있어요 성능, 속도, 성능에 신경 쓴다면요
If you care about accuracy, that kind of performance, then you could you could use the total.
정확성에 신경 쓰신다면, 성능에 신경 쓰신다면 합계를 이용하실 수 있어요
The open LM score, that that, uh, aggregate score as your measure of model accuracy.
오픈 LM 점수요 모델 정확도의 척도로써의 총점이죠
If you care about the cost in terms of the memory footprint and a sense of the of the magnitude of hardware
메모리 공간 측면에서 비용을 고려하고 이 모델을 실행하기 위해 필요한 하드웨어의
that you're going to need to run this model, then you need to look at the size of the blob.
크기를 고려한다면 blob의 크기를 봐야 해요
A bigger blob represents a greater memory need, and so it gives you a sense of what you'll need there.
큰 덩어리는 더 많은 메모리 수요를 나타내요 여러분이 필요한 게 뭔지 감을 잡게 해주죠
So we are looking ideally for models that are small blobs that are over on the left and that are quite
저희가 찾는 모델은 작은 점으로 왼쪽 위쪽에 있는 게 이상적이죠
That would be a nice result for us if we don't need it to be high up.
높은 곳만 아니면 좋은 결과가 나올 거예요
Particularly you can see a model like this one is doing really, really well and it is a Quan the Quan
특히 이런 모델이 아주 잘 되고 있는 걸 볼 수 있어요 Quan the Quan
1.5 variant.
1이죠 5가지 변형이 있어요
Um, if you look right up here, if what you care most about is something which perform, which has
여길 보시면 가장 신경 쓰이는 건 성능이 뛰어나고
very great, very strong accuracy in terms of its benchmark scores and is also quite fast.
정확하며 벤치마킹 점수 면에서 빠른 기술이죠
Uh, then maybe you come to this one here, which you can see is Llama Llama three model.
그리고 이 제품으로 오세요 라마 라마 3 모델이에요
And that does bring me to the final point, which is that the other, uh, bit of information that's
여기서 마지막 요점이 등장합니다 이 도표에 표현된 또
being expressed in this chart is the family of models, but that is expressed by the color of blob.
다른 정보는 모델의 가족인데 비트의 색깔로 표현되죠
And you can see over here, uh, how to read those colors like yellow means it's a phi model or a Phi
여기 보시면 노란색은 파이나 훈련을 받은 모델이란 뜻이에요
And you'll see the phi, uh, yellow model over there.
저기 노란색 파이 모델이 보일 거예요
So when it comes to the trade offs between speed, accuracy and memory footprint, which will affect
속도와 정확도, 메모리 풋프린트의 양면성에 있어서 오픈 소스 모델의
your running costs, uh, for open source models, this is a fantastic resource.
실행 비용에 영향을 미칠 텐데 이건 환상적인 리소스예요
The, uh, perf leaderboard, uh, come to this, always turn to the Find your Best Model tab and browse
leaderboard를 눌러보세요. 여기로 오세요. 항상 당신의 가장 좋은 모델 찾기 탭을 누르세요.
around to understand what your options are.
그리고 당신의 옵션이 뭔지 살펴보세요.
And this for example, if we're talking about a T4 hardware, then you would flip to the T4 tab to see
예를 들어 T4 하드웨어를 이야기할 때 T4 탭으로 가서 어떤
what kind of, uh, options you have here.
옵션이 있는지 볼 수 있어요
And looking that's the 01I hear.
보세요, 01I 청음이에요
Is Kwan again doing well.
콴은 잘 지내고 있나요?
And you can see other other models that might be most appropriate for you based on your use case.
다른 모델도 볼 수 있어요 사용 사례에 따라 가장 적절한 모델이죠
And now I just want to mention that there is a spaces uh, there is a you could you could go to spaces
제가 말씀드리고 싶은 것은 빈 공간이 있는데 빈 공간으로 가서 leaderboard를
and search for leaderboards.
검색할 수 있어요
All I've done here is done a leaderboard search in spaces, and you will see all of the different leaderboards
여기서 한 건 공간에서 leaderboard를 검색한 것뿐입니다
that are out there that you could look at to see more details about your benchmarks of your LMS.
다양한 leaderboard를 볼 수 있죠 LMS 벤치마크에 대한 보다 상세한 정보를 볼 수 있어요
And if you're not overwhelmed with the amount of information here, there is great, great utility to
여기 있는 정보의 양에 압도되지 않으셨다면 제가 조금 전에 언급한 이 다양한 leaderboard를 보는
looking at these different leaderboards I mentioned a moment ago.
데에 아주 훌륭한 유틸리티가 있어요
There is a Portuguese focused leaderboard.
포르투갈이 집중해서 순위를 매기고 있어요
You'll find many languages have their own leaderboards specifically to assess the abilities.
많은 언어가 독자적인 순위표를 갖고 있어요 능력을 평가하기 위해서요
I mentioned the open medical leaderboard.
오픈 메디컬 리더보드를 언급했죠
Let's bring this one up and you can see that there's a bunch of medical specific benchmarks like clinical
이걸 띄워 보면 여러 의학적 벤치마크가 있습니다 임상 지식, 대학
knowledge, college biology, medical genetics, uh, and uh, and PubMed QA.
생물학 의학 유전학, 그리고 퍼브메드 QA 같은 것들이죠
And these are then scored against medical models.
의학 모델과 비교해서 점수를 매겨요
So if you were trying to build a solution that was designed for medical use cases, this is the leaderboard
의료 유스 케이스용으로 설계된 솔루션을 개발하려 한다면 바로 이 순위표를
that you would come to right away.
봐야 해요
Um, and so really the and typically the, the, the about page will give you that extra information
어바웃 페이지는 추가 정보를 제공합니다 데이터 집합과 어떻게 사용되고
about the data sets, how it's used, how they are calculated.
어떻게 계산되는지에 대해서요
So this should give you a really good sense of how you select the right set of, of uh, open source
이걸 보면 문제가 발생했을 때 올바른 오픈 소스 모델을 어떻게 선택할지
models for the problem at hand.
감이 올 거예요
How you find a useful leaderboard and how you, uh, interpret the different metrics and can rank the
유용한 순위표를 어떻게 찾고 다양한 지표를 어떻게 해석하고 다양한 모델을 어떻게 순위
different models out there.
매길지 말이죠
Next time we'll look at some leaderboards that combine open source and closed source.
다음 시간에는 오픈 소스와 폐쇄 소스를 결합한 리더보드를 살펴보죠